[
  {
    "type": "vocabulary",
    "word": "symi",
    "example": {
      "sentence": "[symi].",
      "translation": "[(a) man]."
    }
  },
  {
    "type": "short-response",
    "direction": "foreign-native",
    "prompt": "symi.",
    "answers": ["a man", "man"]
  },
  {
    "type": "short-response",
    "direction": "native-foreign",
    "prompt": "A man.",
    "answers": ["symi"]
  },
  {
    "type": "vocabulary",
    "word": "cévo",
    "example": {
      "sentence": "[cévo].",
      "translation": "[(a) woman]."
    }
  },
  {
    "type": "short-response",
    "direction": "native-foreign",
    "prompt": "A woman.",
    "answers": ["cévo"]
  },
  {
    "type": "short-response",
    "direction": "foreign-native",
    "prompt": "cévo",
    "answers": ["a woman", "woman"]
  },
  {
    "type": "vocabulary",
    "word": "lá",
    "example": {
      "sentence": "[lá].",
      "translation": "[He/she/it/they exist]."
    },
    "tip": "[He/she/it] is the implied subject. If context demands it, [they] may be the implied subject."
  },
  {
    "type": "grammar",
    "description": "The verb 'lá' is at the center of most sentences in Nóri. Without an object, 'lá' may signify 'existance'.",
    "syntax": {
      "highlight": "[interjection]",
      "sentences": [
        {
          "phrase": "lá cévo.",
          "meaning": "He/she/it's a woman"
        },
        {
          "phrase": "symi lá.",
          "meaning": "A man exists."
        }
      ]
    }
  },
  {
    "type": "short-response",
    "direction": "foreign-native",
    "prompt": "lá.",
    "answers": [
      "to be",
      "he is",
      "she is",
      "it is",
      "they are",
      "he's",
      "she's",
      "it's",
      "they're",
      "to exist",
      "he exists",
      "she exists",
      "it exists",
      "they exist"
    ]
  },
  {
    "type": "short-response",
    "direction": "native-foreign",
    "prompt": "They exist.",
    "answers": ["lá"]
  },
  {
    "type": "vocabulary",
    "word": "miro",
    "example": {
      "sentence": "lá [miro].",
      "translation": "He/she/it is [(a loaf of) bread]."
    }
  },
  {
    "type": "short-response",
    "direction": "native-foreign",
    "prompt": "It's a bread loaf.",
    "answers": ["lá miro"]
  },
  {
    "type": "short-response",
    "direction": "native-foreign",
    "prompt": "She is Sophie.",
    "answers": ["lá Sophie"]
  },
  {
    "type": "short-response",
    "direction": "foreign-native",
    "prompt": "David lá symi.",
    "answers": ["David is a man", "David's a man"]
  },
  {
    "type": "short-response",
    "direction": "foreign-native",
    "prompt": "lá cévo.",
    "answers": [
      "he is a woman",
      "she is a woman",
      "it is a woman",
      "he's a woman",
      "she's a woman",
      "it's a woman"
    ]
  }
]